Uh this is a world historic moment. It
either could be the resolution of the
Israeldriven hostility of the United
States [music] to the Islamic Republic
of Iran, or it could be the precursor of
a war throughout [music] the world.
Hi, I'm John Kuryaku and welcome back to
another episode of Deep Focus. We're
recording this on Thursday, February
12th. And the reason why I give you the
date is that this is a very important
day in Washington. Benjamin Netanyahu is
in town, obviously, to lobby President
Donald Trump to to bomb Iran and to do
Israel's dirty work for it. But also
this morning, the president announced
that he was giving very serious
consideration to moving a second
aircraft carrier battle group to the
Persian Gulf. Right now, the USS George
HW Bush is off the coast of Norfick,
Virginia. It is supposed to remain in
the Atlantic Ocean for the next couple
of months doing maneuvers and exercises.
Instead, it looks like it's going to be
steaming east through the Mediterranean,
through the Suez Canal, around the
Arabian Peninsula, and right up to
Iran's borders. This is a very troubling
troubling development because
the United States can't make war against
Iran. One aircraft carrier battle group,
the USS Abraham Lincoln, and its 11
accompanying ships are in the Arabian
Sea right now. But it can make war
against Iran with two aircraft carrier
battle groups. We're going to talk about
this with one of the most important, one
of the most insightful political
analysts anywhere in the world. I am
very proud today to tell you that George
Galloway is joining us. Mr. Galloway is
a British politician. He's a broadcaster
and a writer. He has been the leader of
the Workers Party of Britain since he
founded that party in 2019. He's a
former leader of the Respect Party until
2003. He was a member of the British
Labor Party from 1997 to 2010. From 2012
to 15 and again in 2024, he was a member
of Parliament for five different
constituencies.
Mr. Galloway does not join us from the
UK. He's joining us from Moscow. Why?
Because he was harassed and detained at
Gatwick airport for more than 5 hours
recently, just like our friend,
Ambassador Craig Murray, constantly
harassed as he enters and leaves his own
country. So, George Galloway, thank you
so much for joining us.
>> The honor is mine, John. Uh, I've
followed your work for many years. Thank
you. and I'm a great admirer of your
soul and I'm very happy to be with you
this evening.
>> Oh, thank you so much. I feel exactly
the same way about you. You have a way
of cutting directly to the chase in your
analysis and there's so much that I want
to ask you about and so much of it is is
intertwined with with other issues. You
can't talk about Iran without talking
about Israel. You can't talk about
Israel without talking about Gaza. So,
let's start with Iran. I've been in
touch o over the last several weeks with
um with uh an Omani official and the
Omanis are great peaceloving people.
They always always act as the
intermediary between the United States
and Iran. They always offered to host
talks between the United States and Iran
and have done that more times than I can
recall.
We hear from both sides that the first
round of indirect talks between the
United States and Iran that took place
in Muscat about a week ago u were were
positive. Those talks were positive even
if they were indirect. I'm not really
sure what positive means. whether it
means neither side ran screaming from
the room uh or if if that there was some
kind of substantive um component to it
that they could agree on. I I think just
the former is the truth, but give us
your thoughts on the current situation
between Iran and the United States and
how you assess what appears to be the
deployment of a second aircraft carrier
battle group. Now,
>> well, uh, first of all, I share your
admiration for the Sultanate of Oman, my
favorite Arab country and, uh, the only
country which has, uh, a door open, uh,
to both sides and, uh, therefore a very
strategically important uh, place and
uh, we must all pray and hope that uh,
their mediation efforts uh, will succeed
this time because if they don't, the
gates of hell will open and not just in
the Persian Gulf but across the world.
Uh this is a world historic moment. It
either could be the resolution of the
Israeldriven hostility of the United
States to the Islamic Republic of Iran.
Or it could be the precursor of a war
throughout the world. Not a world war,
but a war throughout the world. because
Iran is no pushover as they proved in
the 12-day war last year and are ready
to prove uh in multiples if the shooting
war begins again. So uh of course Donald
[snorts] Trump is negotiating. We know
his uh style of negotiation is to uh
browbeat and bludgeon and maybe even
bribe uh the parties to bow to his
demands. The Iranians on the other hand
are in no need of his money and uh
certainly not the kind of people who
could be bludgeoned or browbeaten. I
think uh something that I should say
that isn't widely uh appreciated
uh the Iranian leadership are entirely
religiously devoted people. Uh therefore
death in conflict with the great Satan
is uh is a positive thing for them. It's
uh a ticket to heaven for them. So you
can't really intimidate someone who is
ready to fight you to the death and
moreover believes that it's a ticket to
paradise. I think a lot of western
commentators underestimate that point. I
mean, we've had uh Trump uh last year
and again recently explicitly and
implicitly threatening the uh supreme
leader of Iran as if such a man can be
meaningfully threatened, threatening him
with uh with death uh when uh such a
death would be a glory to him. So uh
it's important that we uh walk a mile in
the other fellow's shoes and the other
fellow's shoes uh are that this is the
47th year of war. Uh this is not
something that happened uh just last
year uh or at the uh advent of the uh
October 7th post October 7th relations.
uh Iran has been at war with the United
States and the broader west, its
satropes in Europe and indeed in the
Persian Gulf itself. Every year of the
47 years now of the Iranian revolution
has been a year of confrontation, either
kinetic confrontation or terrorist proxy
confrontation. and all of the 47 years
under economic sanction, quarantine,
embargo and siege. So the fact that the
Iranian revolution is still standing and
is entirely uncorrupted politically
speaking, still holding to the
principles that founded the revolution,
uh gives you some idea of the adversary
that Donald Trump has picked, the
adversary that he's chosen to fight.
>> [snorts]
>> Now, if I may segue uh to the point you
made uh in your introduction that uh
Benjamin Netanyahu is in town, but when
is he not in town? This is the seventh
time that Netanyahu has visited
Washington and Donald Trump's only been
in for a year and two weeks. Uh now I
mean that's uh a level of intimacy uh
that uh would be troubling uh in any
circumstances but troubling more because
it's self-evident that Netanyahu is not
there to see what he can do to help the
people of the United States. He's not
there to help you with the
infrastructural problems that are uh in
abundance in your countries. He's not in
uh the United States for any positive
purpose, but merely to procure more
money uh to hold out that begging bowl,
but even worse, uh to uh seek the United
States to uh agree to risk the lives of
its men and women in these uh these
battleship groups, these floating
coffins that you call aircraft craft
carriers uh not one but now two giant
floating coffins uh either in the area
or sailing towards it. So in part this
is the Trump style of negotiation. Uh
you could call it the sopranos but it
doesn't have the class of the sopranos.
Uh it's uh it's a low-level gangsterism
uh of the kind that wouldn't look good
even in a Hollywood movie. uh it is do
what I tell you or I'll kill you. Um and
uh I just think that they've chosen the
wrong adversary on this occasion. It may
be that Donald Trump has spent so much
time uh with the uh neighbors of Iran
that he thinks they're all cheap uh
cheap dates. uh he thinks they'll all
fall into his deadly embrace at the uh
whiff of Donald Trump perfume, but the
Iranians are not like that. And uh if
this war begins, uh it will be a long
time before it ends and it will not end
without very severe losses on the
Western Empire side.
>> Let me ask you about about Israeli
demands. First of all, I want to preface
it by saying that the CIA has written
not one but two national intelligence
estimates, the highest level sense of
the intelligence community publication
that exists in the US government. Two
national intelligence estimates, both
concluding that the Iranian government
has not and is not seeking a nuclear
weapon. Number one, we have the the CIA
saying this directly to the president.
The Iranians do not have a nuclear
weapons program.
So now the demand is that the Iranians
not enrich any uranium at all and
whatever uranium has been enriched has
to be turned over to the United States.
Now that's changed from a year ago. a
year ago it was it had to be turned over
to the United Arab Emirates or to the
Saudis or who who knows. The second
demand is that the [clears throat]
Israelis I'm sorry the second demand is
that the Iranians forego any missile
program at all.
I'm I'm hardressed to think of any other
country on earth that has had this
demand uh placed before it where it is
not permitted to defend itself. Now I'm
I'm thinking this is because the
Israelis were surprised that the
Iranians were able to defend themselves
during the 12-day war. And indeed, the
conventional wisdom is that the Israelis
used all of their own defensive missiles
and have not yet had the chance to
replace them. I'd love to hear your take
on this. Are these are these points
non-starters?
Well, don't forget, John, that Donald
Trump already destroyed all of Iran's uh
nuclear material in a top gun raid that
he uh boasted about endlessly. Uh just
in the last uh less than 12 months, uh 7
8 months. Uh so how how then did Iran
become again a nuclear threat? Now,
you're right to say that the national
intelligence findings are that Iran does
not have and does not seek uh a nuclear
weapons uh option. Uh more fool them. I
say the reason you and I are talking now
about the imminent perhaps attack on
Iran, but never have we discussed any
imminent threat to attack North Korea is
because North Korea does have a nuclear
weapon. The moral of that story is not
hard to grasp. I mean, a school boy,
school girl could conclude that the only
way to stop the United States bullying
you or invading and attacking you is to
have a nuclear weapon. So, more fool
them uh for religious reasons,
theological reasons because uh nuclear
weapons, weapons of mass destruction are
weapons unlimited in space and time. uh
the previous leader of Iran Ayat
uh declared them unislamic and that's a
fatwa to which they hold and uh despite
my advice uh they are definitely uh
holding to it as your own national
intelligence services have testified. So
uh that's a a complete red herring.
First of all, the nuclear material was
destroyed last year, according to the
president. Was he lying then or is he
lying now? That's a question you'd need
to ask him. But in any case, whatever
enriched uranium they possess, they are
not seeking to turn it into a nuclear
weapon. and the IAEA, the referee that's
supposed to judge these things,
repeatedly uh reported that in the uh
the previous um P5+1
nuclear uh agreement that President
Obama concluded uh with the Iranians.
So, it's a big red herring. The second
of the demands, as you rightly uh infer
with the skepticism in your voice, is a
demand that could not possibly be
accepted by any country. Uh that uh
certainly any country that had enemies.
Uh could not agree not to have any
missile defenses. uh this is uh a recipe
for Iran being entirely at the mercy of
uh Benjamin Netanyahu and not many
people would agree uh to that
proposition. But there is a third
proposition uh which is equally
unacceptable, a non-starter if ever
there was one. The third demand is that
Iran has uh to cut all its relations
with friendly countries and friendly uh
movements. In other words, it's got to
tell the brave Yemenes, the only Arab
country to stand up for the people in
Gaza uh in the last couple of years uh
at great cost to themselves. uh the only
people in the world who actually acted
on the decisions of the International
Court of Justice to oppose and interdict
uh the commission and the carrying out
of genocide by their economic sanctions.
That's what they were. They said nobody
will be allowed to sail across our
waterways with material that could be
used in a genocide. Uh so they were the
only country in the whole world that did
that. Uh so Iran has to cut relations
with them, has to cut relations with
Iraq. Uh you and I both came in on this
point. Uh John, uh I warned Tony Blair
and George W. Bush. Uh, the destruction
of Arab power in Iraq could only lead to
a massive enhancement of Persian power
in Iraq. And so it came to pass. They
did destroy uh the Arab power that was
there. And the Iranians now have uh the
closest possible relations with their
neighbor in Iraq. And why shouldn't
they? Uh so according to the demands of
Donald Trump, they should cease to have
such relations with their neighbor Iraq.
So there's three demands, none of which
are negotiable. Uh and if that's the
sticking point, well, it's war. But one
must ensue
that they don't really expect Iran to
break relations with its allies. Iran is
a massive uh soft power country. Uh it
has soft religious and soft national
power. Uh right across the Muslim world.
I mean there are people in Pakistan
right now. There are people in England
right now uh that are praying for the
for the safety of the Islamic Republic
of Iran. They are they they are a global
soft power. Um which could turn into
hard power uh if a shooting war begins.
Of course uh it's unlikely that the
Yemenes will allow the United States to
pulverize Iran without themselves uh
intervening in the war. It's unlikely
that the Iraqi militias will do so. It's
unlikely that the Hezbollah, their other
ally in South Lebanon, will do so. It's
unlikely that there are correligionists
everywhere in the world will sit on
their hands whilst uh United States
warplanes and missiles rain down on
Iran. So um we must assume that ser
voices than are evident in Donald
Trump's hourly press briefings uh have
told the president this including in the
Pentagon because everything that I know
and you know the Pentagon knows.
Everything that I know and you know the
CIA knows. So, um, one must assume that
they haven't abrogated their
responsibilities and have told the
president this. And here's a point you
might find controversial. I don't think
Donald Trump wants to go to war with
Iran.
>> Why Netanyahu is in the Oval Office
right now? Because he knows that Donald
Trump would prefer a negotiated outcome
to this. And for a reason, for all the
reasons I've given, but for an
additional reason,
Trump and his family, his grasping
in-laws, uh, included, have real
material interest in the Arab countries
in the Persian Gulf, which will no
longer exist as we know them if a war
begins. all these countries that empty
their gold and and diamonds and pearls
and uh gifts of aircrafts and uh golden
camels and all the rest. All these
countries will will cease to exist as we
know them if a war uh begins between the
United States and these Arab countries
in the Gulf are a effectively a bank for
the Trump family business. So that's an
additional reason for not creating when
there is absolutely no need to a
shooting war the consequences of which
are incalculable and the end result of
which is unfathomable.
I think you're 100% correct. And you
know, one of the ironies in this whole
thing too is when the media speculate
about what kind of of settlement we
could possibly see were one to be
negotiated
looks almost identical to the JCPOA that
was that was negotiated between the
Obama administration and and uh the
Iranian government. the the JCPOA
was working
in terms of of keeping u controls on the
Iranian nuclear program. It's exactly
the same settlement that was negotiated
between the IAEA and the Iraqi
government. The same kinds of seals, the
same cameras that were that were mounted
at the entrances to the to the different
nuclear sites. It was exactly the same
and it was all verifiable and it was
working. And then Donald Trump withdrew
from it unilaterally and is trying to
force the Iranians to go right back into
it. But along with these other Israeli
demands of no ballistic missile program,
no uh uh uranium enrichment and the cut
off of relations with Iran's closest
friends in the region. I I also have to
agree with you, George, that there's
real danger here for Bahrain, for the
United Arab Emirates, for Saudi Arab
Arabia, especially in the eastern
province, which is where most of the oil
is. This isn't going to be a country of
92 million people just just rolling over
and accepting defeat, you know, without
a shot being fired. And and one final
point too, I don't know why the Western
media are not talking about the fact
that Iran has developed hypersonic
missiles. The United States doesn't have
hypersonic missiles. We're working on
one, but we don't have any idea what a
hypersonic missile might do to an
aircraft carrier, for example.
I have an idea. Uh even the uh even the
Yemenes have hypersonic missile uh
capability. It's extraordinary that the
United States does not. Uh but these
hypersonic missiles are essentially
undefendable. Uh they can only be
defended at disproportionate cost at the
exhaustion of scarce anti-missile
uh uh weaponry and systems. Uh so uh
they are as George W. Bush would put it,
they are misunderestimating
uh the Iranian uh military capability
which has of course been greatly
enhanced since the 12-day war of last
year. First of all, China and Russia
have been shipping in like billio uh big
transporters with electronic warfare
with anti-aircraft capability. Uh Iran
is much stronger than it was uh in the
12-day war and Iran did not use its
cuttingedge missiles in the 12-day war,
but we'll certainly use them in the uh
in the next war if war there is. So
there are multiple reasons for not
beginning this war. Uh I'm so old. I
remember the Vietnam War. The Vietnam
War cost the United States of America
58,000
of its soldiers uh and airmen. Uh it uh
cost the United States uh blood and
treasure of unimaginable proportions.
And it was begun by people who had no
idea how it would end, when it would
end, in what circumstances it would end.
And we all know it ended with the
scramble on the roof of the American
embassy in Saigon as was uh with
helicopters lifting off with people
hanging on to the legs of the chopper.
Uh and uh it ended in total ignimonyy
and defeat for the United States. And uh
I remember cheering it, if you'll
forgive me saying so uh with with great
heartiness. But uh the uh consequences
of a war on Iran are incalculable. I
described your two aircraft carriers as
floating coffins. They're floating
coffins, by the way, without the use of
hypersonic missiles. Iran's missile
drone uh hypersonic uh capacities are
being gravely underestimated
and they're all dug very very deep. No
one will be able to preemptively destroy
them. So every way you dice it, John,
it's really better not to do this.
>> Yes. Folks, before we go on to our next
question, I'd like to pass on a message
from our sponsors. A single government
appointee could cost you your
retirement, and most Americans don't
even know that it's happening. What you
do know is that Kevin Walsh is being
positioned to lead the Federal Reserve.
What you might not know is that he's the
quiet architect behind a central bank
digital dollar. That's programmable
money. And now he's one step away from
making it real. This means your money
could be tracked, frozen, or even spent
without your permission. It's already
happening in other countries. And once a
government gets control like this, they
rarely if ever give it back. If you
value privacy and independence, you need
to understand what's coming. There's a
free guide called the digital dollar
trap. It explains what's happening
behind the scenes and how physical
assets like gold could help protect your
savings from centralized control. Go to
johnlovesgold.com
to get your free copy or call 888
gold053
to request one by mail. That's
johnlovesgold.com
or 888 gold053.
Um, you know, I want to ask you too
about uh lessons learned from the 12-day
war because I think that the United
States has missed a lot of the lessons
that should have been learned during the
12-day war. You'll recall that Israel
attacked Iran and the Iranians responded
by sending a wave of drones. It was
something like 600 drones. The Iranians
warned the Israelis in advance that the
drones were coming, but they had to save
face because they had been attacked.
Well,
all of those drones were were shot out
of the sky, but seven. That's very
valuable intelligence that these slowm
moving drones that you have 6 hours
advanced notice are on their way over
still penetrated that vaunted iron dome.
And then we see reports that the
Israelis used literally all of their
surfacetosurface missiles, their
surfaceto-air missiles. they have to
replenish them. It seems like it would
be an incredibly stupid thing to do to
launch another war because it's not
going to turn out the way the last one
did. And when you attack a country of 92
million people, which has very strong
allies, especially in Russia and China,
that can resupply their missiles, I just
don't see the upside for the Israelis
and especially for the Americans to want
to go to war in the first place. Well,
neither can I. But of course, they uh
both Israel and the United States
frequently act against their own
interest. Indeed, the whole MAGA uh
platform program idea concept has uh has
become MAGA is the last thing it is. It
is not America first, it's Israel first.
It's not MAGA, it's MIGA. I know these
are uh cheap slogans, but they happen to
be true. Uh and therefore, you cannot
rule out the United States doing
something extraordinarily stupid. Now
they may imagine, I advise them to
unimagine that, but they may imagine
that they can uh fire some desultry
uh broadside against Iran and then
declare victory uh and then retire uh uh
telling everyone again like they did
before that the top guns have done their
job. But I think the Iranian warning
should be taken seriously that any
attack on Iran will be treated as
fullcale war and with the response uh to
the best uh and maximum of their
capabilities. I don't think the Iranians
are bluffing over that. And I don't
think the American allies hosting the US
military bases in the Arab countries
nearby and maybe not so nearby because
Iran has missiles that can travel many
thousands of kilometers. A lot of
American bases, a lot of American
interests will be in the direct line of
fire. And of course you uh rightly
pointed out something which I merely
accentuate now uh that the eastern
province of Saudi Arabia is where all
the oil is but it's also where all the
Shiites are. The Shiites being the
correligionists of the Islamic Republic
of Iran. So, uh, it's bad luck for the
Americans that God put Saudi Arabia's
oil underneath the land, uh, that is
populated by by, uh, correligionists
of the, uh, Islamic Republic of Iran.
So, you'll have Iraq, you'll have, uh,
the eastern province of Saudi Arabia,
you'll have Qatar, where the biggest
American military base in the world is
situated. You'll have the United Arab
Emirates, a big fat juicy target which
is the subject of particular
in Thran. uh they feel particularly
betrayed uh by the United Arab Emirates
and its closeness to Israel, its
constant intrigue with Israel uh and uh
and the extent I mean one of the reasons
why is the Iranians built Dubai and
having built it uh they may very well
feel that they have the right to destroy
it if uh if the UAE E is as it clearly
is in league with the Americans in any
uh any new war. So as I say given that
all these countries are the source of
much laress not just for the United
States but for the Trump family
personally for Kushner personally. It
would be one hell of a risk to uh launch
a war against Iran which might lead to
the killing of the golden goose that
lays so many golden eggs for Trump's own
family.
Yes, that would be dangerous. I I want
to switch if we could or shift I should
say uh to uh the issue of of Gaza and
the Israeli occupation of of Palestinian
lands. We're seeing a resurgence here in
the United States of of what
what are being euphemistically called
real estate seminars. Now, these are
being held at uh at synagogues in New
Jersey, New York, Toronto, advertising
land that's available uh for purchase at
very low low prices um in the West Bank
and in Gaza. Of course, this is
Palestinian land that is being stolen by
the Israeli government and turned over
to settler groups. And we we still see
like we have for years, Israeli settlers
bulldozing Palestinian olive uh olive
trees, for example, setting fire to
homes and building new settlements. And
in the meantime, Benjamin Netanyahu
seems to be getting away with this
policy of not just allowing Palestinians
to leave, but encouraging them to leave
and not allowing them back in.
>> Where do you think this is going? This
is the very definition of ethnic
cleansing.
uh for sure uh uh I wouldn't be
investing uh if I were uh the people
attending these seminars uh for multiple
reasons. Uh I'll leave aside the moral
reasons uh because I know that most of
these investors would not be interested
in any moral argument that I have to
make on it. But uh first of all, the
Gaza Strip is Hiroshima. Uh it's
actually Hiroshima times five. Uh it is
entirely toxic and contaminated land as
a result of five Hiroshimas worth of
high explosive uh and uh of course the
consequent death of hundreds of
thousands of people. Many of them
unburied uh many of them uh having
seeped not to put too fine a point on it
into the water table into the soil. It
will never be glad confident mourning in
the Gaza Strip. Uh even if you buy a
condominium built on the skulls of
Palestinian children and even if that
does not haunt you, and I hope it does,
uh you may very well find that it's not
the healthiest place to live. Second,
the Palestinian resistance hasn't gone
away, you know, and uh a Trump Tower or
a casino or a bordello or a condominium
uh is going to be prime targets forever
more for Palestinian resistance groups
uh who will be the grandsons of the
martyrs who were slain in the uh
conflict uh that we saw since October 7.
Thirdly, and uh I hesitate almost to
make this point because international
law seems to have gone out of fashion,
but it would be flatly illegal uh to buy
uh land from peopledeed who whose
property it does not is not uh and of
course whose property it is has already
just last year been re-emphasized by the
highest court in the world, the
International Court of Justice, which
has again declared, reaffirmed
that this is Palestinian land. It is
occupied territory under international
law. Now, that might mean nothing to
Netanyahu. clearly means nothing to
Donald Trump, but it might not mean
nothing to a judge somewhere who is
called upon to adjudicate a land dispute
uh between someone that says that
condominium's built on my land and I
never agreed to sell it. It might be a
problem for governments
uh including my own uh which have
already recognized a Palestinian state
based on the borders agreed in the Oslo
agreement. Now those borders include the
entirety of the Gaza Strip. So how do
you buy a piece of land and from whom do
you buy it?
And there's an additional peonc here.
Netanyahu said just the other day that
Israel fully intends to take full
control of all of the Gaza Strip, but
Donald Trump says he already owns it.
His board of peace already owns it. Uh
now that's a therefore a double land
dispute. Netanyahu thinks it belongs to
him. Donald Trump thinks it belongs to
him. But international law says it
belongs to the Palestinian people as
part of what has now been illegally
occupied territory uh since uh 1967.
It's a very very long time, but it
doesn't cease to be occupied territory
just because the thief has managed to
hold on to it for a very long time.
Folks, before we move on to our next
question, I want to bring you another
word from our other sponsor. I want to
talk to you about something that's
important to me, and that's medical
freedom and being able to make your own
health care decisions. That's why I'm
proud to partner with All Family
Pharmacy. They're a US-based licensed
compounding pharmacy that works with
licensed providers to give people access
to medications like Ivormectin and
Mabendazol and they ship directly to
your door. Let's be honest, when flu
season hits or when the system gets
overwhelmed, the last thing you want is
to be scrambling, dealing with delays,
or being told that you can't get what
you and your family might need. Being
prepared is not political. It's just
smart. I like All Family Pharmacy
because they believe, as I do, that
patients should have options. They
should have privacy and the right to be
proactive about their health. You don't
wait until your house is on fire to buy
a fire extinguisher. Well, it's the same
idea here. So, take control and get
prepared today. Go to allfamilyfarm
pharmacy.com/j
and use my code john10 to get 10% off
your order. That's allfamilyfarm
pharmacy.com/jjoh
and the promo code is jonn10.
George, is there any reason at all to be
optimistic about any facet of what's
happening in the Palestinian
territories? Just yesterday, day before
yesterday, um,
Minister U, uh, Smootrich, the Minister
of Finance, who's also the national
security
minister of the the West Bank or
whatever his silly title is, um, said
that the that the Israeli government's
policy would be to expel all
Palestinians, all of them. and they've
made no attempt to hide the fact that
that's the policy. Uh, but we have Oslo
on the books. We have countless United
Nations Security Council resolutions and
General Assembly declarations.
Is there any reason to be optimistic?
[snorts]
>> Uh, well, I wish I could say yes, but I
have to say no. Uh I have been involved
in this Palestinian issue for 50 years,
50 years. Uh and uh we're in a worse
position now than we were 50 years ago
uh on multiple levels. There are some
levels on which we're better off. The
height of support for the Palestinian
cause in Western countries agreed is of
course exponentially greater now than it
was 50 years ago. But the Arab the Arab
side of the equation is uh immeasurably
weaker uh than it was 50 years ago. Uh
so um on most levels uh we are uh worse
off than we were when the Palestinians
had a PLO which was the if you like uh
holding uh group for all Palestinian
resistance factions when the Palestinian
cause was situated
within
the broader
uh progressive movement. ment when there
were socialist countries that would
support it diplomatically and in other
ways. Uh the Palestinian under Arafat
with the PLO were far stronger than they
are now with this
93y old joker. Uh
>> I always say
16 years into a four-year term.
Uh well, [laughter] when I first knew
Mahmud Abbas, he was an old man and that
was 40 years ago. He looked and sounded
and acted like an old man when I first
met him 40 years ago. And he's still
acting at least as the Palestinian
president. But I I shouldn't be too
rude. I'm often uh I'm often chastised
for that. Uh but uh I'm trying to make
the point that my friend Yaser Arafat
was in a much stronger position even
though the Palestinians were not on the
land. The liberation movement was not
present on the land. Uh they had no uh
kind of government on the land. But what
has been gained uh by having Abu Mazan's
government on the land? What has been
gained by having his goons uh using
their weapons on the Palestinian
resistance in the West Bank uh acting as
the security force of Netanyahu's
Israel? Well, not very much has been
gained by that. Uh the only thing that I
could say to cheer you up is that the
Palestinian cause will never die. Arafat
used to say in fact he said it thousand
times to me even though every time I
chastised him that it was not very
politically correct. Arafat used to say
we are not the red Indians. We are not
going into the museum. uh we we will not
be uh an object of people's fascination
uh inside a glass case. Uh I used to
tell him we don't say red Indians
anymore uh uh chairman but uh it the
next time he still repeated the offense.
Uh but the uh but the point that he was
making is true. The Palestinians will
never surrender. And I mean never
surrender. I mean the grandsons and the
greatgrandsons
of the people who fell in Gaza over the
last couple of years, they will still be
fighting for their rights. The I tell
you a story. I was on a speaking tour of
Canada. I was in the Arctic Circle in
Yellow Knife. In the Arctic Circle, it
was 47° below. I went out onto the great
slave lake where someone had drilled in
the ice uh a nice fishing hole for me to
try my hand. And as I approached the
young woman who was doing the drilling
in the Arctic Circle in Yellow Knife,
Canada, I saw that she was an Arab. I
said to her, "Where are you from?" She
said, "I am from Hifa." Now, she wasn't
from Hifa. Even her parents had never
seen Hifa. Her grandparents had been
expelled from Hifa. But that girl and
her children and her grandchildren will
still be from Hifa. This is a cause that
will never die. And so the
apartheite state, the settler state, the
ideology that stole the land will never
have a moment's peace. They will never
be able to relax and think that they
have gotten away with this gigantic
crime and neither will their uh their uh
descendants.
George, if you don't mind, I want to uh
switch over to something that has become
an important domestic political issue
here in the United States, and that is
the the release of at least half of the
Jeffrey Epstein files. Uh there are no
good guys in this uh in this situation.
The Democrats and Republicans are
equally guilty of either committing
crimes against children or covering up
crimes against children or pretending to
normalize crimes against children. But
one of the one of the areas of fallout
that that we're seeing is is really the
the implosion of Peter Mandlesson, the
the former British ambassador to the
United States, former senior Labor Party
leader. There's been some coverage in
the UK pre press uh highlighting the
fact that there are Labor Party
backbenchers who are questioning the
judgment of Kier Starmer. You knew what
kind of person they're saying Mandlesson
was. He's a crook. He's always been a
crook and now he's a pedophile and a
crook. So, the buck has to stop
somewhere, as we say here in the United
States. Do you think this is the
beginning of the end for Kier Starmer as
the as the head of the Labor Party? And
what kind of broader fallout might this
have in British politics?
[snorts]
>> Well, uh, he he might be gone by the end
of the evening. uh but
>> didn't even last as long as the head of
cabbage.
>> Yes. Uh but I'll come back to that. Far
be it from me to correct a master as
such as yourself. But uh in fact, it was
2,700,000
pages that were released, not the 3
million that they said they were
releasing. So there's a missing 300,000
there. And it definitely wasn't the six
million pages. that they earlier told us
existed. So we're missing 3,300,000
pages. And if they are anything like the
the 2 million 700,000 then crowned heads
and prime ministers and uh and uh
oligarchs of all kinds in business in in
media uh and in diplomacy, the royal
courts of Scandinavia and so on. Uh God
knows who will be the next uh casualty.
But to deal uh precisely with your
question, Kier Starmer was in uh a whole
lot of trouble before the Mandelen
scandal. Uh his premiership has resulted
in a an approval rating amongst the
general public of precisely 10.5%.
uh another uh 6 of a percent and he's in
single figures. There have never been
statistics like this in the whole
history of polling. He is the most hated
prime minister of my lifetime and
probably uh since uh democracy if we can
call it that was introduced uh in our
country. He is reviled uh not just
because he is uh uh singularly
incompetent but because he lacks even
the basics of uh political leadership. I
mean as you know I I hated Tony Blair.
He expelled me from the Labor Party
after 36 years of membership because of
my role opposing the Iraq war. Uh, but I
would be the first to concede that Tony
Blair was pretty good at what he did. He
looked and sounded and acted the part of
a British prime minister. He had some
finesse. He had some felicity or verbal
felicity, physical felicity. Starmer is
a block of wood and he started off as a
block of wood and it's gotten worse and
worse and worse. The wood worm is well
and truly eating him up from the inside.
Then comes along this grotesque
error of judgment which he now claims uh
he stumbled into. Didn't know uh then
what he knows now. And these are all
lies.
All he had to do was read my social
media, and I know that he does, or
people do on his behalf. Uh, I've been
exposing Peter Manderson's relationship
with Jeffrey Epstein for years before
uh, Star gave him the Plump Post as
ambassador to Washington. So, he really
has no excuse. And the British people
know he has no excuse. And believe it or
not, you know, you wait a long time for
a London bus and then two come along at
once. Well, only a day later, another
pedophile lord uh was unmasked
uh by the media who are in full uh
fullthroatated pursuit now. Uh a bit too
late, but they are. Uh it turns out that
man that uh Starmer appointed another
guy as a member of the House of Lords.
For your American viewers, that means a
member of the legislature for life and a
and a red and white hermine coat to go
with it to look uh grand and medieval uh
when you're doing it. uh he appointed
him as a peer knowing as he has now
acknowledged knowing that this guy was
intimately linked to a multiple child
sex offender. So, I mean, Starmark had
not much to commend him, but he's now on
such a run of bad luck that, as I say,
he'll be lucky to last the evening. As a
former British Prime Minister, Harold
McMillan once said, it's not this damn
thing. It's not one damn thing, it's one
damn thing after another. And that's the
grip that uh Kirst is now in.
>> And I want to ask you, George, about
your own situation. My my good friend u
uh Ambassador Craig Murray has had
problem after problem after problem just
entering and exiting his own country
because he has had the unmitigated gall
to stand up for Julian Assange for
Wikileaks for the Palestinians. Now
you're facing the same challenges that
he's facing. tell us about what's
happening with you and and the and the
things that you've had to do to protect
yourself.
[snorts]
>> Well, he's even higher ranking than me.
An ambassador is the equivalent of a
cabinet uh minister. It's why you
[snorts] call them excellency. I still
call Craig uh your excellency. Uh in in
British uh constitutional terms, an
ambassador is the equivalent of a member
of the cabinet. And yet that ambassador
Craig Murray was arrested under the
terrorism legislation
and his devices confiscated and told
that he was under investigation for
terrorism.
Now I was a mere humble member of
parliament but I was elected seven
times. I was a member of parliament
across [snorts] five decades from the
1980s, 1987
until just over a year ago. uh seven
times elected member of parliament if I
may say so. One of the better known
people in the country uh with a big
audience uh the leader of a political
party which obtained a quarter of a
million votes in just a few
constituencies that we contested. Uh I
uh as I say uh swore allegiance
against my better judgment to her
majesty the queen to his majesty uh king
Charles as recently as uh as 20uh 24. So
uh for me to be arrested at gunpoint
by anti-terror police told that I was
not under arrest but I was not free to
leave that I had no right to silence if
I refused to answer any question. I
would automatically, imagine that,
automatically be guilty of a terrorist
offense
and would never fly on an airplane
again. Try getting on an aircraft with a
conviction for terrorism, the policeman
said. And unknown to me, my good wife
was held for even longer than me in an
adjacent room without any uh knowledge
on my part that she also had been taken.
And uh we were grilled
uh on in her case her Palestinian
fingernail. She has a fingernail painted
in the Palestinian colors on her uh
Islam. Uh how faithful to Islam was she?
What practice, what uh what uh uh
tendency in Islam did she uh support?
She's not even a British citizen, by the
way. She's an Indonesian national. Had
no intention of ever becoming a British
citizen. Uh, and I told the police, uh,
you have now made it impossible for me
to live in this country because my wife
will not remain in Britain having been
held at gunpoint by cops under the
terrorism laws. That's just not
something she'll be prepared to do. And
so it has uh turned out. I was grilled
on 30% of the questions were on China.
Why do I have relations with China? What
are those relations? What exactly are my
attitudes to this or that uh issue
between Britain and the People's
Republic of China? They grilled me about
Chinese spying in the Houses of
Parliament, uh about the uh intentions
for the Chinese embassy in London. And
so I mean 30% of the questions were
about China. And what did I find when I
was in Shanghai
just last week? I found Kier Star Tmer
whose police officers they were
following me around in Shanghai begging
the Chinese leadership for a strategic
partnership. Whilst for the policemen in
October, China was a danger to Britain's
national security.
Last week, Kier Starmer and I were both
in Shanghai and he also in Beijing
meeting the Chinese president begging
for some crumbs off the Chinese table.
70% of the questions were about Russia.
I'll give you a laugh. Uh at one point
the police officer, this is the
political police by the way, not just a
Bobby off the street,
he said to me, "Why do you admire uh the
Russian foreign minister Lavough? Why
have you said repeatedly that you admire
him?" My answer was, "Everybody admires
Lavro. Every ambassador in the world
regards him as a master of his craft."
When did you last meet Lavough? They
asked me. Only a couple of months ago, I
said. I shared a platform with him. And
the cop actually said to me on camera,
"What? A railway platform."
I didn't know whether to laugh or cry.
This is the caliber of the political
police sent to grill me, a seven times
member of parliament. So after I
laughed, I said, "No, a stage, a
platform, an event."
He thought I meant a railway platform.
>> Oh my god, he was serious, George.
>> He was totally serious.
>> I thought he was just taking a swipe at
you.
>> Serious.
>> These people are not James Bond.
>> Oh, this is painful.
>> They're Austin Powers
>> or Mr. been. And they are have the gall
to question me, a figure in the land to
send a policeman of that caliber
with his gun on show throughout
to ask me questions about China and
Russia. And if I didn't answer them, I'd
be automatically guilty of a terrorist
offense. So to answer your question, uh
John, we have uh declared ourselves uh
in exile. You you might say if you were
being humorous, I'm the British
government in exile uh in China and
elsewhere. and uh I intend to stay out
of Britain until I have an assurance
from the British government that no such
indignity will happen to me again. I
don't think my wife will go back to
Britain in any circumstances. Uh but for
me to go back, I would need that
assurance. I'm certainly not at the age
of 71
going to be held at gunpoint by a
policeman that thinks meeting Lavough on
a platform was a chance encounter in a
Moscow railway station.
I I will add before I let you go, I was
stationed at the United Nations when
Sergey Lavrov was the Russian ambassador
to the United Nations and literally
everybody respected him. He's one of the
He is one of the most accomplished
diplomats anywhere on the planet. I've
never met any anybody that didn't have
respect for Sergey Lavrov.
>> Exactly.
>> I wish said that.
>> Yes,
that's what I'll tell them when they
stop me next time in London.
George, I am proud to call you a friend.
George Galloway is a British politician,
a broadcaster, a writer, a legendary
freedom fighter.
>> He has been a member of Parliament uh
covering five different constituencies
over the course of more than 27 years.
Glad to have him. George, thanks so much
for joining us.
>> Welcome. An honor to be on the John
Kuryaku show. The
>> the honor is mine. Thank you.